MEGAN R. WILEY

SUMMARY

I am a University of California, Davis graduate with a B.A. in Psychology and a B.S. in Human Development. I have experience in a wide variety of areas including team leadership, sales, crisis handling, recruiting, customer service, human resources, office management, and event planning.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, DAVIS – Davis, CA

Bachelor of Arts Psychology and Bachelor of Sciences Human Development

EXPERIENCE

STRUCTURAL ESTIMATOR

Paul Davis Restoration - Rodeo, CA - September 2015 to March 2017

Schedule and conduct appointments with insured home or business owners who have recently suffered water, wind, fire, or other structural loss at their property Responsibilities

- Apply a high level of attention to detail and exactitude with measurements and calculations
- Utilize Xactimate 27.5 or 28 software to package property estimates, which include a comprehensive 3D sketch, estimated line items, and verified claim information
- Coordinate with both property owner and insurance adjuster to facilitate a concerted scope; make supplements or change orders as necessary
- Employ proven sales techniques to a sale subsequent to estimate approval
- Draft contracts, manage PMs assigned to sold jobs, track payments, and collect final checks

Accomplishments

- Obtained Xactimate 28 Level 1 and Level 2 certifications in only two months
- Instructed myself to become a Certified Xactimate Trainer on own time

SENIOR OPERATIONS MANAGER

Go-Staff, Inc. - Anaheim, CA - February 2015 to August 2015

Coordinate and supervise branch staff, establish budgets, and monitor expenses to ensure the proper development of the Anaheim branch

Responsibilities

- Identify personnel needs within the branch
- Manage all internal staff's scheduling and productivity
- Provide logistic support to administrative staff
- Delegate responsibilities to other employees
- Maintain excellent client relations through attentive account management

Accomplishments

- Increased weekly revenue from \$0 to \$50,000 in four months
- Gained \$20,000 weekly in personal billing with minimal sales experience in three months
- Recruited, hired, and trained new branch employees for supervisory roles
- Created and developed training programs for all new employees

RECRUITER

Go-Staff, Inc. - Oceanside, CA - August 2014 to February 2015

Screen applicants, conduct interviews, and process all new hire paperwork including background and reference checks

Responsibilities

- Review resumes and select qualified candidates through online resources and cold calling
- Dispatch employees to job sites
- Schedule employees for work, ensuring that all job orders are filled nightly
- Supervise temporary employees and instruct good work practices when necessary

Accomplishments

- Awarded Recruiter of the Month three months in a row
- Implemented new office procedures to improve efficiency
- Promoted and selected to open a new branch after only six months

MUSIC DIRECTOR

The Spokes - Davis, CA - June 2013 to June 2014

Lead rehearsals, teach new material, and coach a cappella group of twelve women at UC Davis

Responsibilities

- Arrange and compose music for performances
- Edit group's marketing materials for distribution through unique and creative outlets
- Serve as motivational figure and vocal role model
- Create and assign exercised designed to improve technique

Accomplishments

- Founded the A Cappella Council, the first organization of its kind to build unity among groups within the a cappella community
- Developed marketing strategies to sell out final performance at the renowned Mondavi Center with over 2,000 attendees

CUSTOMER SERVICE ASSOCIATE

Yolo County SPCA Thrift Store - Davis, CA - June 2013 to September 2013

Organize donations, handle finances, and provide excellent customer service

Responsibilities

- Maintain in-stock and presentable condition assigned areas
- Stock and refill register area inventory
- Adhere to the execution of established safety, security, store operations policies, procedures and practices

Accomplishments

- Promoted to online sales clerk after three weeks
- Independently operated satellite SPCA store after four weeks